Ungar, Frederick; Papers ger092
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Frederick Ungar Papers1931-1989
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Ungar, Frederick
ger092
11.12 cubic ft.
This collection contains correspondence, book catalogs, and research materials of Frederick Ungar, especially those relating to the Frederick Ungar Publishing Company.
Biographical History
Frederick Ungar was born and educated in Vienna, where he founded Phaidon Verlag and Saturn Verlag. He founded the Frederick Ungar Publishing Company in 1941 and directed it from its offices in New York City for more than forty years. Ungar edited or introduced many volumes on German and Austrian literature. Frederick Ungar died in 1989. Some titles from the Frederick Ungar Publishing Company are now owned by the Continuum International Publishing Group.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains correspondence with Bruno Bettlehem, Franz Rudolf Bienenfeld, Edward L. Ericson, Erich Fromm, Alexander Gode, Fritz Hochwlder, Norman Lear, Robert Lohan, Viktor Mateja, Thomas Mann, Jan Masaryk, Will Schaber (with translations into German), Joseph Liutpold Stern (with manuscripts of poetry), Ernst Waldinger, Marie Weiss, Thornton Wilder, and others; Ungar's notebooks, 1959-1968; working materials for Ungar's unpublished German-English dictionary, 1945-1957; copies of early imprints, and catalogs and other promotional publications of the Frederick Ungar Publishing Company, 1941-1988. There also are subject files, including ones about honors and awards, biographical materials, A. Gode, Austrian in poetry and history, the American Pictorial Encyclopedia, the Barash arbitration, and American women writers.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is unprocessed, but there is a general arrangement at the box level.
Acquisition Information
All items in this manuscript group were donated to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives by Hansi Ungar. 1990
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted.
Literature; Publishers and publishing --Austria; Authors, Exiled; Correspondence; Manuscripts; Notebooks; Book catalogs; Ungar, Frederick; Fromm, Erich, 1900-1980; Gode, Alexander, 1906-1970; Frederick Ungar Publishing Company
- Frederick Ungar Publishing Company Dust Jacket Covers, Undated (Box 1 (Frederick Ungar Papers), Item 1)
- Correspondence re: German-English Dictionary, 1947-1955 (Box 2 (Frederick Ungar Papers), Item 1)
- Subject Files and Correspondence, A-Ba, 1963-1983 (Box 3 (Frederick Ungar Papers), Item 1)
- Subject Files and Correspondence, Be-E, 1940-1989 (Box 4 (Frederick Ungar Papers), Item 1)
- Subject Files and Correspondence, F-K, 1948-1985 (Box 5 (Frederick Ungar Papers), Item 1)
- Subject Files and Correspondence, L-S, 1941-1986 (Box 6 (Frederick Ungar Papers), Item 1)
- Subject Files and Correspondence, U, 1940-1987 (Box 7 (Frederick Ungar Papers), Item 1)
- Subject Files and Correspondence, V-W, 1949-1986 (Box 8 (Frederick Ungar Papers), Item 1)
- Subject Files and Correspondence, W-Z, 1975-1985 (Box 9 (Frederick Ungar Papers), Item 1)
- Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1948-1981 (Box 10 (Frederick Ungar Papers), Item 1)
- Correspondence re: German-English Dictionary, Including Files of Correspondence with Robert Lohan, 1943-1957 (Box 11 (Frederick Ungar Papers), Item 1)
- Materials for Unpublished Dictionary, 1947-1956 (Box 12 (Frederick Ungar Papers), Item 1)
- Notebooks, 1959-1968 (Box 13 (Frederick Ungar Papers), Item 1)
- Catalogs and Brochures from Frederick Ungar Publishing Company as well as Other Publishers, 1969-1970; Undated (Box 14 (Frederick Ungar Papers), Item 1)
- Catalogs, Brochures, and Dust Jackets from Frederick Ungar Publishing Company, 1972; Undated (Box 15 (Frederick Ungar Papers), Item 1)
- Catalogs, Brochures, Dust Jackets, and News Releases from Frederick Ungar Publishing Company, Undated (Box 16 (Frederick Ungar Papers), Item 1)
- Early Galleys and Imprints, Undated (Box 17 (Frederick Ungar Papers), Item 1)
- Catalogs from Frederick Ungar Publishing Company, Undated (Box 18 (Frederick Ungar Papers), Item 1)
- Materials for Unpublished Dictionary, 1952; Undated (Box 19 (Frederick Ungar Papers), Item 1)
- Calendars/Monthly Planners, 1957-1964 (Box 20 (Frederick Ungar Papers), Item 1)
- Dust Jackets and Correspondence, 1963-1985 (Box 21 (Frederick Ungar Papers), Item 1)
- Books Published by Frederick Ungar Publishing Company as well as Other Publishers, 1931-1974 (Box 22 (Frederick Ungar Papers), Item 1)
- Books Published by Frederick Ungar Publishing Company as well as Other Publishers, 1937-1988 (Box 23 (Frederick Ungar Papers), Item 1)